Eric Alcaide

C/ Pisuerga n2, 7o2a, 08028 Barcelona, Spain • ericalcaide1@gmail.com • +34625429886

ericalcaide • EricAlcaide

Skills

Multi-langauge coding

Python, Bash, Julia, JavaScript,

C++, Web

Scientific Computing

Scientific Python, Julia, Bash

Problem Solving

Initiative, Creativity, Originality

Cloud Computing

AWS, Google Cloud

Fast Prototyping

Public Speaking

Machine & Deep Learning

computer vision, sequence analysis, classification, clustering, sentiment, regression,

adversarial attacks, search

methods...

Teamwork

adaptability to different organizations and team

structures

Projects

2017 – 2019 Open Source Projects

Created several projects and modules for scientific computing which recieved a high degree of community acceptance:

- **2019**: **MiniFold** ☑ **:** Predict protein foldings from raw sequences (AlphaFold imitation).
- 2018: Keras-WRN ☑ : A package of Wide Residual Networks for image recognition in Keras
- 2018: SearchMethods.jl 2: The Julia package for Search Methods algorithms.
- **2017**: **Pysimplechain** □: Python implementation of a simple blockchain in less than 200 lines of code.

2017 – 2018 Al Research Paper, *E-swish: Adjusting Activations to Different Network Depths* PrePrint proposing a new activation function called E-Swish which showed state of the art results in several computer vision benchmarks.

2017 – 2017 Deep Learning – Can Computers learn? ☑

Research project focused on the AI and Deep Learning field, subfields and the state of the art techniques.

• Exploration of usage of Evolutionary Strategies for architecture optimization in Neural Networks.

Professional Experience

2019 – 2020 Machine Learning Instructor, *Private Tutor*

Given personalized advice and taught Masters' students from different backgrounds (from Computational Linguistics to Biomedical Engineering) different topics: generally speaking about Data Science, AI and ML, and specifically about Text Classification, Image processing and Information representation.

Successfully advised how to carry out Masters' Thesis-level projects.

2019 – 2019 Al & ML Mentor, NonProfit Hackathon for Medicine: BitsXlaMarató

Barcelona, Advised and assisted different teams during the development of healthcare and

Spain scientific solutions with a strong algorithmic component.

Performed genomic analyses, clustering, HPC (high performance computing) and data

visualizations of complex information. Won several prizes.

2018 – 2019 **Developer,** Several Hackathons

Spain, Got awarded projects on 3 out of 4 hackathons during the past two years: an API for Switzerland mobility data, a decentralized publishing platform and an AI system for psychiatric

mobility data, a decentralized publishing platform and an Al System for psychiatric

patients' follow-up. Hackathon names: Som Hackathon, HackUPC2017 and

HealthHackathon Esade.

2017 – 2017 **Data Analyst,** *Nexow Systems*

Spain Applied Deep Learning models to market data analysis, characterization and

prediction during the summer internship.

Education

09/2020 – **Physics,** University of Barcelona

present Currently studying. Theoretical Physics Degree

2018 – **Medicine,** University of Barcelona

present Currently studying. Exceptional student with multiple distinctions.

2016 – 2018 High School, Pare Manyanet Les Corts, Barcelona

Graduated with Honours - 99.5%

Participated in the Debates club, got seleted for Physics and Chemistry olympiads, scored top 1% of my region in Cangur (Mathematics contest) and recieved a honorific

mention from a EU translate contest.

2017 – 2017 **Artificial Intelligence,** *Columbia University*

Master's Level Course on Artificial Intelligence (edx.org): Applying key concepts of classic AI and Machine Learning to both classic and real problems such as games and

sentiment analysis.

Courses

2020 – 2020 **HPC-based Computational Biomedicine,** Barcelona Spercomputing Centre

Impact and Hands-on experience of applied supercomputing to biomedical problems

(molecular simulations, genomic analysis, tissue modelling...)

2017 – 2017 **Deep Learning Specialization,** *Coursera*

Learned about the foundations of DeepLearning, how to structure projects, computer

vision, and sequential data.

Languages

SpanishNative

Catalan
Native

English German

C2 level A2

Mandarin